Guide to the Michael Klepper Papers MC.145
New York University Archives
Michael Klepper Papers
1984-2010
New York University Archives
Klepper, Michael M.
MC.145
4.38 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
The Michael Klepper Papers document the writings of a public relations expert who graduated from New York University and later became an associate adjunct professor. The collection contains Klepper's research material, correspondence, manuscript notes, and chapter printouts regarding the four books he authored.
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
Arrangement
Material is arranged by book. Within each book's series the correspondence and reviews of each book are ordered chronologically. The files are grouped as follows: I, Getting Your Message Out; II, I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech; III, The Wealthy 100; IV, Gone The Sun.
Material is arranged by book. Within each book's series the correspondence and reviews of each book are ordered chronologically. The files are grouped as follows:
Missing Title
Getting Your Message Out
I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech
The Wealthy 100
Gone The Sun
Scope and Contents
The collection documents the writings of a public relations and speech training expert who graduated from New York University and later became an associate adjunct professor. The vast majority of the collection relates to his authorship of two how-to books, one chronicle of the richest Americans, and a novel. Michael Klepper's steps towards the final published product can be traced through the research articles, manuscript pages, notes, and chapter printouts. The collection also contains his correspondence related to and published reviews of these works.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biography of Michael Klepper
Michael Klepper (b. 1934) graduated New York University in 1957 with a Bachelor of Science degree in business. His career began at NBC News where he wrote, produced, and directed. In 1967 and 1968, the first two years it went national, he was Associate Producer of the Jerry Lewis Muscular Dystrophy telethon. From there Klepper became a senior officer at Burson-Marsteller, where he launched their first Radio & Television and Media Training departments. In 1978 he founded his own public relations firm, Michael Klepper Associates. His diverse clients have included Monsanto, Dow, Showtime, the New York State Bar Association, and the governments of Canada, Japan, and Israel.
A specialist in media and speech training, Klepper has written two training books, Getting Your Message Out: How To Get, Use & Survive Radio & Television Airtime (1984) and I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech (1994). He has written articles for The Wall Street Journal, Investor's Business Daily, and other publications. Additionally, he is the author of The Wealthy 100: From Benjamin Franklin to Bill Gates--A Ranking of the Richest Americans, Past and Present (1996), along with his first novel, Gone The Sun (2010).
Michael Klepper is a member of the Public Relations Society of America Counselors Academy, the International Association of Business Communicators, the American Stock Exchange Arbitration Panel, the American Arbitration Association, and the Conference Board. He frequently lectures for PRSA, IABC, and the Conference Board along with being an associate adjunct professor at New York University's School of Continuing Education.
Sources: -1957 NYU Commencement Roster -Author's Biography; The Michael Klepper Papers; MC 145; Box 5; Folder 3
Books.; Articles.; Mass media.; Management.; Public relations.; Correspondence.; Income.
- Getting Your Message Out
  - Book
    - Getting Your Message Out, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes and chapter printouts of book
    - Getting Your Message Out Chapter Printouts 1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Getting Your Message Out Chapter Printouts 2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech
  - Book
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech 1, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech 2, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notes and chapter printouts of book
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech copy, October 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech Chapter Printout, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech Chapter Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech Correspondence 1, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech Correspondence 2, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Published articles and reviews
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech Research, Undated, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - I'd Rather Die Than Give A Speech Reviews, Undated, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- The Wealthy 100
  - Book
    - The Wealthy 100, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notes and chapter printouts of book
    - The Wealthy 100 in Japanese, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - The Wealthy 100 Chapter Printouts 1, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - The Wealthy 100 Chapter Printouts 2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - The Wealthy 100 Chapter Printouts 3, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Wealthy 100 Chapter Printouts 4, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - The Wealthy 100 Chapter Printouts 5, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence
    - Published articles and reviews
      - The Wealthy 100 Research, Undated, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - The Wealthy 100 Reviews, Undated, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - The Wealthy 100 Correspondence, 1994-2003 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Gone The Sun
  - Notes and chapter printouts of book
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 1, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 2, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 3, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 4, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 5, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 6, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 7, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 8, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 9, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 10, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 11, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 12, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 13, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 14, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 15, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 16, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 17, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 18, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 19, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 20, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 21, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 22, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 23, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 24, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 25, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 26, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 27, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 28, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 29, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 30, Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 31, Undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 32, Undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 33, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 34, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 35, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 36, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 37, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 38, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Printouts 39, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Gone The Sun Manuscript Pages, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Gone The Sun Chapter Outlines, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Gone The Sun Authors' Biography, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Published articles and reviews
    - Gone The Sun Research Articles, 1969-1999 (Box 5, Folder 4)